I see twelve soldiers.
No, wait, there's another seven disguised as civilians.
That's a strong formation they're in.
Whoever's commanding them
knows what they're doing.
I wonder if that means you-know-who is here?
Huh?
If it were you, how would you break through their line?
I have to do a pop quiz?
W-well, I'd start by using poison to knock out
whoever looked like they were in charge-
The moment you did, you would be killed
like a balloon floating through the air.
I'm not sure I follow, but I lost?!
B-Bonfire! What the hell are you doing here?!
If we wanted the Foreign Intelligence Office's help,
we would have asked for it!
Don't get all up in my face.
It's suffocating.
You son of a...
Come here!
I'm Flower Garden, Foreign Intelligence Office.
Welter Barth, Military Intelligence Department captain.
It's a pleasure.
I want all the intel the military has on the situation.
This is the Imperial spy we're looking for.
My guess is they're working with a team.
My bosses would kill to get some dirt on you guys.
If you two get in our way and the spy
manages to escape because of it,
they'll try to get the Foreign Intelligence Office
disbanded before you can blink.
You should sit this one out.
I find you insufferable, but that doesn't mean
I want to see your whole org get shut down.
I appreciate the advice.
Hey!
I-it was nice to meet you.
So, about this spy the military is hunting...
What, did you figure something out?
There was a photo of a woman in those files
who bore a striking resemblance to Annette.
There might be some sort of connection there.
Two Days Before the Others Began Their Search
I'll go ahead and report in to Klaus.
MISSION: Forgetter III
After all, we've got a responsibility to
hand Matilda over to the military.
This is something you need to remember.
When a spy gets captured,
the only fate that awaits them is
a darkness deeper than death.
Hold on! Do you even realize what it is you're doing?
I could ask you the same thing.
She's a spy who snuck into our borders.
She's our enemy.
Be that as it may, she's Annette's mother!
Pull yourself together.
For now, all I'm doing is getting Klaus's input.
And if Teach ordered you to, would you turn Matilda in?
Probably, yeah.
We wouldn't even have to lift a finger.
All we'd have to do is tell the army where she is.
You want Annette to just go along with this,
even though it might get her mother killed?
Yeah. And?
Teach... Teach will know what to do!
He'll think up a fantastic solution.
I'm sure of it.
It will be an idea so good,
you two won't have to fight anymore.
Oh, I like where Erna's head is at.
She's right.
This is Klaus we're talking about.
He'll probably guide us to a perfect outcome
that none of us ever considered.
There's no way to be sure of that!
Here's a little warning for you.
If you choose to help Matilda out,
you'll be betraying your country.
In other words, you'll be betraying Lamplight.
But I guess you aren't even the person
I should be checking in with.
You get it, right, Annette?
I...
Cut it out!
You think she's going to be able to just nod along and
agree when you put her on the spot like that?!
Fine, then for her sake, you can have one day.
But at sunset tomorrow, I'm making that call.
That's your time limit.
Thea, Annette, and you too, Erna...
I trust you'll make the right decision as spies.
Traitor or not,
it would hurt having to put a teammate down.
Annette...
Monika is right.
This is your issue to deal with.
We might have no choice but to contact Teach,
but if we do, that might mean
you never get to see Matilda again.
What do you want to do?
I...
want to see Matilda one more time.
Okay.
Then let's go do that tomorrow morning.
Sorry about all that shouting earlier.
Oh, Big Sis Thea...
Good morning, Thea.
Yo, my tummy's rumbling.
We should go to a bakery next.
Oh, a seagull!
So, today is the day you all head back to school?
Right.
Please look after my daughter for me.
I'll come by and visit once my work winds down.
I'm going to ask you this straight, ma'am.
Actually, there's no need for me to be polite here.
My friend found your passport,
and the name inside wasn't Matilda.
Be honest.
You're a foreign spy, aren't you?
Don’t worry, I'm not going to turn you in.
I just want to know what you're really after.
You're absolutely right.
I'm a spy from the Galgad Empire.
I knew I couldn't use a fake name around my daughter,
so I gave you my real name, Matilda.
I used to be an Imperial engineer,
but when my husband passed away,
I volunteered to become a spy so
I could support my daughter.
Most of my spy work involved transporting funds.
Having a young daughter with me let me draw
less suspicion than I would have on my own.
But then, while I was on a job,
we were in a horrible train crash.
I thought my daughter was dead,
and after that, I went through life in a daze.
Then, my work tools got stolen,
and before I knew it, the army had me surrounded.
But please, Thea, you have to understand.
Understand what?
I know I lied to you,
but when I said I wanted to take back that girl,
my daughter, that part was true.
Was it?
Annette's lost her memories,
and four whole years have gone by.
We can't even be certain that Annette and
this daughter of yours are even the same person.
No, I'm certain.
She hasn't changed a bit.
Her personality's a little bit different,
and she's lost her memories,
but she's still my daughter.
I give you my word.
When I get home, I'm going to retire from being a spy.
I want to live a quiet life with my daughter,
and I never want us to get separated again.
Are you even going to be able to get home?
I don't know...
I've sent so many SOS messages to my homeland,
but all I've been getting is radio silence.
I think they've probably written me off.
I see.
Seeing them like this, they really do look like a family.
The way things stand, Matilda is going
to be tortured and killed.
But if I try to help her...
Monika will just brand me as a traitor and kill me.
"Enjoy that discord."
"Differences between allies are
the key to a strong team."
That's a quote I cribbed off the boss.
Ms. Hearth said that?
There's no truth there.
When people's values are too different,
all it does is make their team fall apart.
What should I do, Ms. Hearth?
So, she's the daughter of a
newspaper company's president, huh?
I feel for you, girlie.
If you wanna be mad at someone, blame your old man
for that garbage he publishes in his rag.
You're the one, right?
The girl who got kidnapped?
My friends are rooting out the rest of the people
involved in the plot right now.
There was probably a puppet master
pulling the strings.
I'm going to look after you until we find them, okay?
Can you not talk?
Ah, you're traumatized from the kidnapping.
Then, can you think of a sentence in your head?
Anything will do.
"What in the world is she talking about?"
It's written all over your face.
Did I get it right?
Luckily, I have some experience with this kind of thing.
There's this boy I took in a few years back.
At first, the only way I could communicate with him
was by watching his face.
The bad news is,
I ended up spoiling him so much he sucks
at holding conversations to this day.
We end up having to learn to read
expressions as part of our job,
but you've got a special skill too, don't you?
If I look someone in the eye,
I can sort of see what's in their heart.
Like, I can sense what they desire.
Whoa! That's impressive.
But I try not to use it much.
People would think it was creepy.
Why don't you try peering into my heart, then?
I mean, aren't you curious?
You want to know who it is you're dealing with.
Wow! Your heart is so pretty.
I'm happy to hear you think so.
Who are you?
I'm a spy.
And I'll do whatever it takes to protect you.
As a spy, what's your goal?
To move war along to its next stage, I suppose.
Isn't the war over?
Nope, war never ends.
But the thing about people is,
we can change the shape that conflict takes.
What do you mean?
The Great War ended,
and now, wars are fought between spies.
Um, you know what?
It's a little hard to explain.
Basically, I didn't want to be a spy.
I wanted to be a hero.
A hero?
Spies can only save their own people.
But heroes, heroes can save so much more.
I...
I want to be like you.
Oh hey, you got your voice back!
Were you mimicking me a little bit there?
I thought that if I copied your tone,
I might be able to talk again.
Am I little closer to being like you now?
You have it in you to become so much more than me.
We won't have long together,
but I guess I should probably teach you a trick or two.
Thinking back now, I realize that she wasn't just kind.
She might have been a little bit extreme, too.
Heya, Sis!
That's a reward from me to you, yo!
Th-thanks...
Where's Matilda?
Over there.
It looked like you were having a nice conversation.
It's all thanks to you, Sis.
Then, could you give me your answer?
What do you want to do?
Do you want to save Matilda?
Or-
Don't worry.
That's not the direction Matilda's hotel is in.
You're worried about her, aren't you?
I think that's just fine.
You should do whatever it is your heart tells you to.
Sis, why are you doing all this for me?
Because when I look at you,
that's what my heart tells me to do.
You can be selfish if you want.
No matter what, I'll accept it.
I...
I want to help my mom!
Then I'll figure out the rest.
MISSION: Forgetter III
How far are you planning on taking me?
We were supposed to be back at
Heat Haze Palace hours ago.
Are you going to betray Lamplight?
If so, I'd appreciate it if you told me.
I'll need some time to dispose of your body.
What do you say to a little change of scenery?
Let's talk this out.
The thing is, I don't think either of us are wrong.
We both have things we refuse to back down on,
and we're acting in accordance with that.
I want to save the people that need saving,
even if it means bending the rules.
You want to do what's right for the team,
and you're not willing to make any exceptions.
What do you say we start from
a position of mutual respect?
Are you done yet?
Look, have you made up your mind?
Are you gonna turn Matilda in,
or are you gonna betray the team?
I'm taking the third option.
Huh?
I'm going to make you submit.
All I have to do is get you to keep quiet,
and I'll be able to get away with
not turning Matilda in
without my duplicity ever being discovered.
I challenge you to a duel.
You get fifty out of a hundred.
Woulda been five more
if you'd gone for a surprise attack.
If you think you're close enough to my level
to get away with fighting fair, you're dreaming.
Then let's get unfair, shall we?
Okay, hold on.
I'm no expert, but I'm pretty sure duels
aren't supposed to involve
calling in a pair of dudes to beat
your opponent senseless.
I can hardly afford to fight fair
when I'm this outmatched, can I?
Screw you, bitch.
Now, whoever takes her down gets a special reward.
Once we're done here,
I'll take your deepest, darkest desires
and fulfill them to your heart's content.
Buzz off, perverts!
That's one.
Shit!
And finished.
Tell me, is that really all you've got up your sleeve?
If so, this is hardly going to be a challenge.
Hey, don't hold back on my account.
Go ahead and use your gun.
Well, someone's sure full of themselves.
Right, you turned Erna into one of your little minions.
I prefer the term "collaborator."
And I've got Annette's help, too.
This fight is really three-against-one.
Now, surrender.
I have no desire to actually harm you.
I don't understand why you're so opposed to this.
You look down on us, you constantly pick fights,
you throw harsh truths no one asked for in our faces...
Why do you even bother staying in Lamplight at all?
And why should I explain myself
to someone weaker than me?
Stay back, or I'll-
It's no use; I can see everything.
No way! How?!
A mirror?
I get it, that's how she saw where the traps were!
We're done here.
You couldn't have failed harder.
You really thought that'd work?
There's no way for me to win.
After all, I'm up against the
strongest girl in Lamplight, but...
That's exactly why I wanted so badly
for you to see things my way.
Trying to tug on my heartstrings?
I feel sorry for you.
You ready to call it?
Or what?
Am I going to have to kill you
to get it through that skull of yours?
I need to put some distance between us,
and make sure she falls for the traps this time.
You're retreating? From here?
Pathetic.
What choice do I have, though?
I'm not like Monika.
I don't have any weapons.
And my special ability can't-
If you hone that ability of yours,
you'll be the strongest spy around.
I want you to become a hero.
Enjoy that discord.
The best approach is to butt heads
with your teammates directly.
Just give up already, you damn slut!
A hero never gives up.
You're going to regret having made me your enemy.
You...
I'm code name Dreamspeaker,
and it's time to lure them to their ruin.
You're dead, you're dead, you're dead,
you're dead, you're dead, you're dead, you're dead!
Tell me, are you in love?
You're dead, dammit!
Wait, did you-
You went to such great lengths to conceal it.
You took those precious feelings,
and you hid them from everyone.
And why? It's simple.
Because the other person is someone close by.
You're in love with someone in Lamplight, aren't you?
You're dead...
You can't kill me.
Think of how sad it would make them.
The reason you want to eliminate Matilda
is to protect Lamplight,
the place your crush calls home.
If we help her, the team might end up
being accused of aiding an Imperial spy.
You're really single-minded in your love.
Quit trampling all over my heart.
Sure, I'll stop.
So, help me out here.
I respect your feelings!
Now, I'm asking you to consider mine!
Shit!
Condition one...
Don't tell anyone about my secret.
Of course not.
I won't bring it up again,
and I won't try to figure out who it is, either.
Condition two: if I ever think the army is
going to figure out what you're doing,
I'm handing Matilda over on the spot.
This one's just as non-negotiable.
Agreed, please do, in fact.
Condition three!
That's a lot of conditions.
About, y'know...
Don't tell anyone that we kissed.
I'll take it under advisement.
You wanna throw down again?
I'm kidding.
If we fought again, I'd end up dead.
If you can agree to all three of those conditions...
then fine, I surrender.
Magnificent.
Why are you talking like the boss, all of a sudden?
Felt like the thing to do.
Honestly, I was the wrong person
to have to play this role.
Lamplight's members all have
a serious ruthlessness deficiency.
We're all too soft.
Even here, I should be putting my
personal feelings aside and stopping you.
This is gonna get us into hot water.
Eventually, we're going to go up against an enemy
that takes advantage of that kindness.
Did it go okay, Big Sis?
Swimmingly.
Monika agreed to help us save Matilda.
Sis!
Don't jump at me.
I'm in a bad mood.
There's no need to be shy.
I'm gonna give you a big ol' kiss, yo!
I've had enough trauma for one day, thanks!
You're under no obligation to take part in this, Erna.
Hey, quit running away! C'mon!
Stay back! Stay back!
You're under no obligation to take part in this, Erna.
The hell's your problem?
Could you tell me how you feel about all this?
I have a condition.
Come back here, yo!
Quit being so clingy, dammit!
Annette, you have to promise
you'll never bully me again.
From now on, I want you to treat me
like a normal f-friend.
If you agree to that, then I'll help out too.
I've thought we were friends this whole time, yo.
Yeep!
Mom, you have to quit being a spy.
Annette meant what she said.
We need you to promise that.
You may have figured it out already,
but we're spies working for the Republic.
We've been competitors this whole time?
That's right.
So, we can't help enemy spies.
That's why you have to retire.
If you can promise that,
we'll help you escape across the border.
But how?
We're going to break straight through
the army's siege.
That's all there is to it.
So? Did you end up reporting in to Klaus?
Of course not.
It's obvious he would object to what we're doing.
He's probably worried about us.
It's morning now, and we're still not back.
It is what it is.
It's time for all of us to disappear.
That's got a scary ring.
But you know what?
I don't hate it.
The four of us will go missing.
We'll be like lost children, yo.
Ah, standing on one leg and feeling the pain
I've shared it with you, are you getting this vertigo?
I've got love, but that's not what's washing over me
I spring up, I spring up, I'm a nuisance and I'm in the way
Am I "really okay"?
What good will asking that do?
Just praise me and be on your way
Blame it on a mirror that's unspeakable, unhealable
A sullied life that's unseeable, unfading
Tear right on through and see through lies with frigid eyes
An innocent item that's unbeatable, unbuyable
It's an undiscarded corpse, after all
Fight back naked with your unconcealed resolve in hand
(whoo, whoo, ooh)
A wishy-washy destiny all covered in graffiti
Recklessly deceiving even God